《神盾局特工》前情回顾
Previously on "Marvel's Agents of s.H.I.E.L.D."...
你就是千里眼吗
You're the Clairvoyant?
他让自己的情感蒙蔽了理智
He let his emotions get the best of him.
他不会善罢甘休的  斯凯
And he wasn't gonna stop, Skye.
我绝不允许那事发生
I wasn't gonna let that happen.
我担心他杀错了人
I'm worried he killed the wrong man.
千里眼没有超能力
The Clairvoyant doesn't have abilities.
他有的是安全权限
He has security clearance.
他是神盾局特工
He's an agent of S.H.I.E.L.D.
为什么梅
Why would May have
在驾驶员座舱有一条未授权加密线路
an unauthorized encrypted hard line in the cockpit?
把枪放下  梅
Put it down, May!
你听谁的命令  谁是真正的千里眼
Who do you answer to?! Who's the real Clairvoyant?!
我们这是去哪儿
Where are we going?
我不知道  不是我干的
I don't know! I didn't do it!
飞机降落后  干掉飞机上所有人
When that plane touches down, take out everyone on board.
除了科尔森特工
Except Agent Coulson.
他是我的
He's mine.
漫威公司出品
翻译：大卫熊  胖兔纯  Silence
■
翻译：爱卿遛小鸟  王大可  章鱼埃克斯
翻译：卫老哥  欧阳  冰蓝  欧沈娜
时间轴：信徒  aaaBao  猫
塔台  我是神盾局E3
Tower, this is S.H.I.E.L.D. Echo-3.
有两架无人机跟在我后边
I got a pair of UAVs on my six.
校对：胖兔纯  大卫熊
友方吗  完毕
These friendlies? Over.
离得再近一点  就要碰到我飞机的喷气流了
They're gonna hit my jet wash, they get any closer.
后期：瓜瓜     总监：米小勒
怎么回事
What is that?
■
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
神盾局特工
第一季 第十七集
《神盾局特工》
神盾局特工
第一季 第十七集
放下武器
Drop the weapon.
-科尔森  -该死的把武器放下
- Coulson. - Drop the damn weapon
踢到楼梯这来  梅  快点
and kick it over to the stairs, May, now!
快
Now!
后退  到那边去
Now back the hell up! Over there!
说  你把飞机航向改到哪里了
Talk. Tell us where you rerouted the plane.
-不是我设定的  我发誓  -别骗我
- I didn't set this new course. I swear! - Don't lie to me!
得了  别装了  飞机都转向了
Yeah, well, the plane just turned around, for god's sake!
不是你  飞机怎么转向的
How is this happening, then?
总部可以改写飞机的自动控制
H.Q. can override automated control of the avionics,
想让咱们去哪就去哪
take us anywhere they want.
让我查看一下仪表操纵板  我就能
Let me check the instrument panel, and I'll be able --
-想都别想  -不解释清楚  你哪都别想去
- No way! - You're not going anywhere till you explain what --
不是我
It's not me!
为什么你有一条加密线路
Why did you have an encrypted hard line?
还有你为什么在被发现后朝我开枪
And try to shoot me when we found it?
-大家都冷静一下  -算了
- Let's take a breath, huh? - Let's not!
那是一条专用线路
It was a dedicated channel...
打给弗瑞局长的
to Director Fury.
这是实话
That's the truth.
弗瑞局长
Director fury?
我几周都没能跟他通上话了
I haven't been able to get him on the line for weeks.
你在向他汇报
You were reporting to him?
我只能说这么多
That's all I can tell you.
别再装了
Oh, just come out with it!
你只能告诉我们这些
That's all you can tell us?!
我在执行命令
I'm under orders!
弗瑞会告诉你的
Fury will tell you.
怎么  开枪也是命令吗
What -- was this an order?
朝我脑袋开枪
To shoot me in the bloody head?
等等
Hold on.
我们这不是去弗瑞那
We're not headed to Fury anymore.
我不知道我们要去哪儿
I don't know where we're headed.
我没法联系上弗瑞  因为菲兹把线路切断了
And I can't get Fury on the line because Fitz cut the line!
斯凯让我切断的
Skye told me to!
有人在与千里眼联络
Someone was talking to the Clairvoyant,
真正的千里眼
The real Clairvoyant.
菲兹  当时你也在那里
You were in the walls, Fitz.
想解释一下  你为什么会鼓捣
You want to explain why you were tampering
卫星电缆吗
with the plane's sat cable?
这事现在不重要
Sure, because that's relevant!
别想把事情扯到我身上
Don't try and turn this around on me!
菲兹
Fitz.
我在试图跟待在中心的西蒙斯联系
I was trying to speak to Simmons at the Hub.
要用到加密线路吗
And you needed an encrypted line?
-干嘛这么神秘  -你说呢
- What's so secret that you -- - Well, you tell me!
西蒙斯和我知道你俩在交头接耳
Simmons and I know you two have been whispering,
不告诉我们
keeping things from us,
救了你们命的药的事情
about the drug that saved your life.
西蒙斯只是想弄明白
Simmons is just trying to figure out
这到底是怎么回事
how the whole thing works!
菲兹
Fitz.
她和谁说过这件事
Who is she talking to?
菲兹  把门打开
Fitz, open the door.
不可能  除非我们把这件事搞清楚
No way -- not until we sort this out.
-我不会打开任何东西  -把门打开
- I'm not opening anything. - Open the door.
你不把门打开我们什么事都搞不清楚
We can't get anything sorted until you open the damn door!
斯凯  用你的笔记本电脑连接我们的系统
Skye, get your laptop hooked up to our systems.
看看能否找到任何神盾局的通讯记录
See if you can pull up any S.H.I.E.L.D. communications.
我想知道飞行的目的地和原因
I want to know where this plane is headed and why.
科尔森
Coulson --
你待着别动
You stay put!
告诉我西蒙斯和谁说过这件事
Now tell me who Simmons is talking to.
如果那人我们信不过
'cause if it isn't someone we trust,
她现在的处境会很危险
she's in serious danger.
西蒙斯特工
Agent Simmons.
我还在想你溜到哪里去了呢
I was wondering where you snuck off to.
你很忙吗
You busy?
是的  但没关系
Yes, but that's okay.
今天这里很吵
It's noisy here today.
很多人都像是在执行任务
A lot of guys in action mode.
我四处打听了
I asked around.
好像是个八级任务
Guess it's a level eight operation of some sort.
我也很惊讶能独占这个屋子
I was surprised to have this room to myself.
那你在忙些什么呢
So, what are you working on?
科尔森的队伍可真是充满了秘密啊
Coulson's team is awfully secretive,
在这里都算是神秘的
even for this organization.
你在隐瞒些什么吗  特工
Are you hiding something, Agent?
没有  不是什么重要的事
No. It's just nothing important.
希望如此
I hope not.
因为我依稀记得我们找到了一种
Because I remember us tracking down a drug
能把一个女孩从死亡边缘救回来的药物
that brought a girl back from the brink,
那东西可是意义重大
and that was real important.
是啊  我知道
Yes. I know.
仔细想了想
Come to think of it,
我好像不记得你有将它上报
I don't remember seeing it in the dispatches,
或是在布莱克特工伤到肋骨的时候
or you mentioning it when Agent Blake
提起这药
got his ribs caved in.
那是因为我
I wasn't in a positi--
因为如果你掌握这种方法但却不去利用
'cause if you had the means and you didn't use them,
那些伤亡也同样要算在你头上
that blood is all over your hands, too.
我知道
I know.
我正在尝试
I'm trying.
听着  有人为了这个秘密失去了生命
Look. Men died to keep this secret.
我们还不明白个中原因
We don't understand why,
所以出于安全考量  目前的研究要保密
so we wanted to keep our research in-house for safety.
-什么研究  -如今遇到了瓶颈
- Research? - That's hit a dead end.
我正在上传斯凯的血液扫描结果
I'm uploading Skye's blood scans.
我想私下里联系
I would like to contact Agent Weaver
神盾学院的韦弗特工
at S.H.I.E.L.D. Academy covertly.
寻求帮助
For a little help.
但这件事一定不能让其他人知道
But we must keep this between us.
拜托了  我不想惹任何麻烦
Please, I don't want any...trouble.
你是五级特工
You're level five?
我的六级权限可以使用
My level-six clearance gives me access
全息可视电话  用的是加密线路
to the holobox -- secure line.
但我们怎么把那玩意弄到这来
But we can't sneak that in here, can we?
汉德特工似乎让所有人都忙得不可开交
Agent Hand seems to be keeping everyone busy.
没问题的
We'll be good.
但是如果有人问起来
But, hey, we get questioned,
让我来应付
let me talk.
你撒谎的能力可真差  西蒙斯特工
You're a surprisingly bad liar, Agent Simmons.
我知道
I know.
但我正在进步
But I'm getting better at it.
你说的噪音是什么意思
What do you mean, "noise"?
就是实实在在的噪音
I mean literally noise
遍布了每一个神盾局通讯频道
across every S.H.I.E.L.D. communication channel.
好像是一种压制信号
Some sort of blanket signal.
-可能是编码过的数据  -我也这么想
- Encoded data, maybe. - I think so.
你想给我们解释一下吗
You want to fill us in?
我们找到了你这个内奸
We root you out -- a mole --
突然间飞机罢工  通讯中断
suddenly our plane shuts down, our communications jammed.
我也不知道怎么回事  我也希望我知道
I don't know what's happening. I wish I did.
-你必须相信我  -不  我不信
- You have to believe me. - No, I don't.
能收到吗  能收到吗  616
Do you read? Do you read, 6-1-6?
这是哪里来的信号
Where's that coming from?
很近
Close.
我被敌方飞机追击  完毕
Enemy aircraft on my tail. Over.
-加勒特  -科尔森  我被攻击了
- Garrett? - Coulson, I'm under attack.
是无人机
Drones.
重复  神盾局的无人机一直粘着我
Repeat, S.H.I.E.L.D. drones are on my ass.
-它们可不是很友好  是否收到  -收到
- We're not getting along. Do you copy? - Copy.
加勒特  出什么事了
Garrett, what's happening?
我们失去了飞机的控制权
We've lost control of our aircraft.
我知道才怪
Hell if I know.
告诉我你那飞机上装备有武器
Tell me you got guns on that thing.
我这就朝你靠拢
I'm coming to you.
菲兹  你能手动把机枪
Fitz, can you manually wire the guns
短接到武器控制室  绕过我们的系统吗
to weapons control, bypass our system?
如果线缆够长的话  可以
If I have cables long enough, yeah.
斯凯  解码信号  我们得先他们一步
Skye, decode the signal. We need to get ahead of this.
今天我可不想再有任何惊喜了
I don't want any more surprises today.
发生了什么
What happened?
她是个沉睡者
She's a sleeper.
我是指卧底的那种沉睡者
I mean the other kind of sleeper.
等等  你在说什么
Wait. What are you saying?
她一直在向别人汇报我们的情况
She's been reporting on us this whole time.
控制激活了  长官
Controls are live, sir.
加勒特  汇报你的位置
Garrett, what's your 20?
我马上就到你的头顶十点钟方向
I'll be on top of you in seconds at your 10:00.
-机枪准备就绪了吗  -预备中
- Guns hot? - Warming up.
他得拉升起来  长官
He needs to pull up, sir.
加勒特  拉升
Hey. Hey! Garrett, pull up!
他知道自己在做什么
He knows what he's doing.
-该死  -那是乔尼
- Damn it. - That's Joanie.
恰奇怎么对付
Any thoughts on Chachi?
现在它可是知道你在这里了
Now it knows you're here.
想玩玩打滚装死吗
Want to roll over, play dead?
好的  菲尔  不过你最好动作快点
Okay, Phil, but you better make it quick.
我快要弹尽粮绝了
I'm running on fumes.
我会拉升到你的水平六点钟方向
I'll pull up even of your six.
最好别失手
Better not miss.
收到
Copy that.
准备好了就开始吧  老大
Ready when you are, boss.
"装死"  那是什么意思
"Play dead." What does that mean?
意思是...我最好别失手
That means... I better not miss.
无人机被击落
The drones are down.
加勒特特工还活着
Agent Garrett's alive
而且与神盾局的空客对接了
and docking with S.H.I.E.L.D. 6-1-6.
我建议我们派更多人手过去
I suggest we send more men,
直接把飞机打下来
shoot that airplane out of the sky.
不必
No.
我们无法取得加勒特飞机的自动控制权
We couldn't seize automated control of Garrett's jet,
所以我本已决定销毁它
So I wrote it off as a loss.
但现在既然他和科尔森对接了
But now that he's with Coulson,
我们就能在着落后把他们一并消灭掉
we can cross him off with the rest when they land.
保存好飞行器
Preserve the aircraft.
你有什么要说的吗  肖特工
You got something to say, Agent Shaw?
对不起  长官
Apologies, ma'am.
我只是觉得杀死我们曾经称为朋友的人
I'm just having a hard time killing
心里难以接受
the people we once called friends.
当那条加密信息发出去后
Once that encoded transmission went out,
一切便从此不同了
Everything changed.
这道理你懂的  不是吗
You understand that, don't you?
我们宣誓忠于彼此
We swore allegiance to each other.
今天  就是考验那份忠诚的时候
And today, that loyalty will be tested.
如果你犹豫不决...
If you waver...
只有死路一条
you die.
这是一条简单的重复信息
It's a simple message repeated.
语义编码
Semantic encoding.
我得先找到助记符
I needed to find the mnemonic key.
再有一两分钟应该就可以破译
It should only take me a minute more to decipher.
我能问一个显而易见的问题吗  搞毛啊
Can I ask the obvious question? What the hell?!
我们也不知道
We don't know.
我们甚至不清楚这架飞机要飞向哪里
We don't even know where our plane is headed.
我看到你们的飞行轨迹了
Oh, I saw your trajectory.
你们正被牵着鼻子直奔中心去
You're being tractor-beamed straight to the Hub.
那些无人机毫无疑问就是从那里出航的
Those drones were launched out of there for sure.
维多利亚·汉德
Victoria Hand.
汉德  不可能啊
Hand? Can't be.
不可能是什么
It can't be what, now?
千里眼
The Clairvoyant.
我还以为沃德干掉那货了
I thought Ward capped that guy.
我不相信沃德杀死的那个人是千里眼
I don't believe the man Ward killed was the Clairvoyant.
我觉得他只是个不知情的诱饵
I think he was an unwitting decoy
用来阻止我们深入调查的
meant to end our investigation.
如此大费周章  看起来可不像是
That's a lot of trouble to go through
在转移注意力  你不觉得吗
for a red herring, don't you think?
因为千里眼是一名神盾局特工
Because the Clairvoyant is a S.H.I.E.L.D. agent
利用高等级权限  总是先我们一步
Using high-level clearance to stay ahead of us,
让她看起来好像有通灵能力一样
make it seem like she's got psychic abilities.
"她"
"She"?
你觉得维多利亚·汉德就是千里眼吗
You think Victoria Hand's the Clairvoyant?
不是我抬杠
I don't mean to pee in the punch bowl,
但是那说不通啊
but that doesn't make a lot of sense.
我和薇曾一起驻扎在里斯本
I was stationed with Vic in Lisbon.
她在派对上的确是又凶悍又扫兴
She's a hard-ass and a buzzkill at parties, I grant you,
但你真觉得她有那个能力吗
but do you really think she's capable of that?
拜托  她刚刚不是想把你炸飞吗
Excuse me. Didn't she just try to blow you out of the sky?
别误会我的意思  她绝对是疯了
Don't get me wrong -- she's definitely gone nuts,
但她的行动不正好证明了她不是千里眼吗
but her actions prove she's not the Clairvoyant, right?
如果她一直以来都避免引起别人注意
I mean, if she's been hiding in plain sight all this time...
那为什么现在要让自己曝光呢
why reveal herself now?
伙计们
Guys.
走出阴影  进入光明
"Out of the shadows, into the light."
这是什么鬼东西
Well, I'll be.
九头蛇
我以为九头蛇在二战之后就被摧毁了
I thought Hydra was defeated after World War II.
没错  神盾局就是在那之后建立的
It was. S.H.I.E.L.D. was founded in the wake of that victory.
现在他们又回来了吗
And now they're back?
九头蛇总能起死回生
Hyrda always comes back.
砍掉一个头  会再生出两个来
Cut off a head, two more will take its place.
是头吗  我还以为是触肢
Is it a head? I thought it was a limb.
-不  砍掉一个头  -砍掉一根触肢
- No, no, no. "Cut off a head." - "Cut off a limb."
是头
It's a head.
但这是从神盾局内部发送的
But it was sent from a S.H.I.E.L.D. source.
这一定是发送给神盾局内部的
It's got to be some sort of activation signal
九头蛇成员的激活信号
to Hydra members within S.H.I.E.L.D.
-汉德肯定是其中之一  -好了  停一下
- Hand must be one of them. - Okay, stop. Stop.
什么意思  神盾局内部
W-what does that mean? In S.H.I.E.L.D.?
瞄准八级探员  夺取权力
Targeting level-eight agents, seizing power.
我想知道有多深入
Wonder how deep it goes.
信号到处都是  很深入
The signal's everywhere. Deep.
-你知道这是什么意思吗  -是的
- You know what this means? - Yeah.
我们完蛋了
We're screwed.
我们不能改变航向
We can't change course,
也不知道在中心等待我们的是什么
and we have no idea what's waiting for us at the Hub.
中心
The Hub.
要我说  咱们把这家伙炸个洞
I say we blow a hole in the side of this puppy
然后跳伞逃走  改日再战
and parachute out, live to fight another day.
我们不能那么做
We can't.
没错  这样是有点窝囊
It's a cherry ride, I'll give you that,
但我们总不能束手就擒吧
but let's not just hand over the keys.
西蒙斯在中心  我们必须救她
Simmons is at the Hub. We have to save her.
糟糕  崔普也在那儿
Oh, crap. Yeah. Trip's there, too.
不得不说咱们胜算不大
I don't mind saying I don't like the odds on this one.
我们应该把你的特工都放出来
We should let your specialists out of their cage.
物尽其用  人尽其才
We can use every weapon we can get.
我们必须救她
We've got to save her.
那我们就飞过去  直面音乐[困境]
So we'll fly in there, face the music...
哪怕是九头蛇之歌
...even if it is the Hydra theme song.
崔普利特和西蒙斯特工下落不明  女士
Agents Triplett and Simmons are unaccounted for, ma'am.
正在进行搜索
Searches are under way.
他们无处可逃
They don't have anywhere to go.
不要小瞧科尔森的手下
Don't underestimate Coulson's people.
赶紧找到他们
Tie up those loose ends.
你确定这条线路安全吗
You're positive this line is secure?
是的  但你得快点
Yeah, but be quick.
偷偷摸摸看起来最可疑
Nothing looks more guilty than sneaking around.
我给她发了一条请求  她一定没有
Well, I sent her a request. She must not have --
韦弗特工  谢谢你能来
Agent Weaver, thank you for joining me.
-我还  -珍玛  谢天谢地你还活着
- I'd been hop-- - Jemma. Thank god you're still alive.
什么  出什么事了
What? What's wrong?
中心还安全吗  你跟你的队友在一起吗
The Hub still secure? Are you with your team?
找个安全的地方躲起来  锁好门
Get somewhere safe and lock the door.
发生什么事了
What's happening?
报告你的指挥官  学院已经被包围了
Have your commander report that the academy is under siege.
我们不知道九头蛇已经渗透进神盾局多久了
We don't know how long Hydra's been inside S.H.I.E.L.D.
他们正在夺取掌控权
They are taking control!
九头蛇  什么  在哪儿
Hydra? What? Where?
到处都是  就在我们中间
Everywhere! Among us!
如果你活下来了  你知道去哪儿找我
If you survive, you know where to find me.
珍玛  不要相信任何人
Jemma, don't trust anyone!
你在做什么
What are you doing?
照这位女士说的  把门锁起来
What the lady said to do -- locking the door.
让我出去
Let me out.
请自便
Go ahead.
如果他们找来  这扇门是顶不住的
This door won't hold if they come looking,
但他们一时半会儿不会找来
but they won't come around this way for a little while.
反正我是不会出去
I'm staying.
我怎么知道能不能相信你
Well, how do I... know I can trust you?
因为我向来忠厚老实
Because I'm trustworthy.
而你才是
You're the one who works
帮那个死而复生的奇怪家伙干活的人
for the zombie robot back from the dead.
拿着
Take it.
如果你用它来攻击我  我就知道你信不过了
If you try to kill me with it, I'll know I can't trust you.
把那玩意重新启动
Now fire that thing back up.
看看能不能联络上我们的朋友
Let's see if we can get our friends on the line.
真迫不及待要告诉他们这个"好消息"了
Can't wait to tell them the good news.
科尔森说你是个内鬼
Coulson said you're an informant.
有什么要解释的吗
Want to elaborate on that?
没有
No, I don't.
该死的冰冻枪
Damn icer.
我的头疼死了
My head's killing me.
我有权知道
I deserve to know.
别提那事行吗
Don't start with that.
服从命令绝不多问  你知道的
We do our jobs. End of story.
在弗瑞批准前我什么都不能告诉你
I can't tell you any more until Fury gives the go-ahead.
你真厉害
You're good.
我向来都听说你很厉害
I mean, I always heard you were good.
但不得不说
But, man...
这么久来你一直将我们玩弄于鼓掌之间
Playing us this whole time,
欺骗我  科尔森
conning me, Coulson.
我没有玩弄任何人  我跟你们同一阵线
I wasn't playing anyone. I had your backs.
还暗地里向别人报告我们的情况
And reported on us behind them.
你一直告诉我要控制好自己的情绪
You know, you always said to keep my emotions in check.
这点上你实在是令人叹为观止
But this is some next-level --
你应该听我说的
And you should have listened.
你冷血地杀了一个人
You killed a man in cold blood,
让你的情感蒙蔽了理智
let your emotions get the best of you.
那是为了保护我们的团队
It was to protect our team from a monster!
你只是为了保护她
It was to protect her!
这么做也情有可原
Which would be okay
但可惜你杀错了人
if you hadn't shot the wrong guy.
菲茨修复好了你的加密线路
Fitz repaired your direct line.
如果你真是清白的
If you have the ability to make this right,
是时候证明自己了  我想你也玩不出什么花样
now's the time, 'cause you can't make it worse.
我有指示不能在旁边有人时干这个
I have orders not to do this with anyone else present.
他们在攻击我们的武器
They're taking out our guns.
立刻打给弗瑞  不然我就把你第一个推出去
Get director Fury on the line, or I'll march you out there first.
长官  发生了什么事
Sir, what is going on?
一言难尽
A whole lot.
谁在攻击我们
Who is shooting at us?
来  我跟你讲讲情况
Come here. Let me catch you up.
如今  显然汉德特工才是千里眼
Apparently, Agent Hand is the Clairvoyant,
你先消化一下这个吧
So chew on that first.
梅琳达·梅特工
Agent Melinda May.
语音指令  紧急协议一号
Voice command. Emergency protocol one.
紧急协议一号
Emergency protocol one.
你好
Hello.
这应该是一条接通弗瑞局长的
This is an X10 straight connection
X10加密通讯专线
to Director Fury's personal line.
他在哪
Where is he?
弗瑞局长死了
Director Fury is dead.
弗瑞的事是真的吗
Can that be true about Fury?
他曾是我和科尔森的监管人员
Man was my S.O. Coulson's, too.
他不止一次证明过他不会那么容易死的
proved himself more than once to be a hard man to kill.
但外面的动静听起来的确不妙
That sound outside doesn't bode well, though.
这飞机上有什么东西
Is there anything on this plane
是你们不想让他们得到的吗
you don't want them to get their hands on?
那是他的专线  菲尔
That was his direct line, Phil.
看来是真的
So it's real.
那如今知道这事的就只有你我了
That means it's just you and me,
除非你还向什么其他组织汇报
unless there were other parties you reported to.
我没有
There weren't.
那就坦白一切吧  弗瑞都不在了
Then come out with it. Fury's gone.
如今我们还在被自己人攻击
We're being shot at by our own people.
弗瑞知道你会邀请我加入
Fury knew you'd want me to join up,
所以他让我留意你
asked me to keep an eye on you.
留意我什么
Looking for what?
任何显示你生理或心理出现问题的征兆
Signs of physical or mental deterioration,
定时向他汇报
to keep him updated.
就是这么单纯
It's that simple.
这么说你一直知道塔希提岛的事情
Did you know about Tahiti?
你怎么能这样对我
How could you do that to me?
我们经历过这么多风风雨雨
After all we've been through,
一起出过这么多任务
The years we spent together in ops --
他交待过一定不能让你知道
He said it was essential you couldn't know.
还有我与你一起搜索巴林岛废墟的那次
The time I spent sifting through the ashes with you in Bahrain?
当我组建这个团队时  我给了你第二次机会
I gave you a second chance when I assembled --
组建团队的人是我
I assembled this team.
你说什么
What?
我负责评估需要的人选
I evaluated what was needed,
然后上交评估结果给弗瑞
and I gave the assessment to Fury,
然后他才给你的参考人选名单
and he gave you the parameters for your unit.
都需要什么人  梅
What was needed, May?
能治愈你身体的人
Someone who could repair your body,
能重建你的大脑的技术员
a technician who could reprogram your brain,
以及在必要时刻能毫不犹豫
and a specialist to help me put you down
把你放倒的专业人士
if it had to be done.
但我不是为了弗瑞
But I didn't do it for Fury.
我是为了你  为了保护你
I did it for you, to protect you!
我
I --
你对我很重要
You mean a lot to me.
非常重要
A lot.
当我听说你死了的时候
To hear you were dead...
你也许不信  但我说的都是真话
You may not believe me, but that's the truth.
而且我和这次千里眼
And I have nothing to do with the Clairvoyant
或是九头蛇的阴谋无关
Or this Hydra threat we're up against.
我挨这一枪就能证明我的清白
Hopefully this helps prove that.
我很想信你
I want to believe you,
但你一直在利用我的信任
but you've used that against me this whole time.
对方停火了
They stopped firing.
从窗户看  没发现敌人的踪迹
No clear shots through the windows.
他们想留着飞机
They want to preserve the aircraft.
接下来就该地面清除部队登机了
A surgical strike team is next.
菲兹破坏了货舱门的液压系统
Fitz cut the hydraulics on the cargo ramp.
他们只能硬撬
They'll have to pry it open.
但这不会挡住他们太久
That won't hold them long.
我们必须想个突围计划
We need to plan to get out of here
带走一切带得走的东西
with whatever we can take with us.
说到这个
About that.
084  阿斯加德武器
The 0-8-4 specs, Asgardian weaponry,
传送装置  多尼的天气控制器
portal creation, Donnie's weather machine.
还有如果重力鎓化物落到他们手里
If they get their hands on gravitonium in the fridge --
鎓化物不在冷藏柜里  没有入库记录
It's below the fridge. No records.
但他们还是有可能
Okay, but on the off-chance
获得将其武器化的方法
we'd give them the designs to weaponize it.
还有塔希提的药  长官
The drug from Tahiti, sir?
全在这
All here.
如果九头蛇彻底控制了这架飞机
If Hydra is really about to seize this plane --
我们得清除系统
We should wipe the system.
我正将其备份到硬盘上以防万一
I'm backing it up on this hard drive to keep our edge.
那就这样  全面清理飞机
Then do it. Scrub the plane clean.
我需要点时间
It'll take some time.
那我们给你创造点时间
We're working on buying you some.
说真的  这个信号阻塞了所有通道
I'm telling you, this signal is clogging everything up.
肯定大事临头了
Something terrible has happened.
不许动  举起手来
Freeze! Show me your hands!
把手举起来
Show me your hands.
这叫老鼠打洞器
It's called a mouse hole.
可以切割任何东西
Cuts through anything, really.
我一年前就设计好提交测试
I designed it a year ago and submitted it for testing,
但从没有配发前线人员
but it never reached distribution.
顶尖特工喜欢把好东西占为己有
Top agents always hog the good stuff.
你说得对  硬盘的安全就靠你了
You're right. The hard drive's safer in your hands.
你还没教我怎么扛住酷刑呢
You haven't taught me how to hold up under torture yet.
回头就教你  很有趣的
We'll get to that. It's real fun.
好  我们分头行动
All right. Here's where we split.
-斯凯和沃德选哪边  -我们去控制中心
- Skye and Ward? - Heading to the nerve center.
废了他们的系统
Disable their systems,
更重要的是夺回飞机的控制权
most importantly, their control of our plane.
明白
Copy that.
记住  这些特工只是受命而行
Remember, these agents are under orders.
只准用冰冻枪
Use icers only.
我们去找西蒙斯  把她救出来
We'll find Simmons, get her out.
我们应该去找汉德
We should go straight for Hand.
九头蛇不是总啰嗦着
Hydra's always talking
什么把头砍掉之类的废话么
about getting their heads cut off, right?
我们的首要任务是救出西蒙斯和崔普利特
Saving Simmons and Triplett -- that's our priority.
我同意  这就是我的办法
I agree, and that's how I'd get it done.
你有更好的办法就说出来
Hope you have a better plan.
菲尔  我能帮忙的
Phil, I can help you if you --
我们是需要你帮忙  但手铐不能解
We need your help, but the cuffs stay on.
你们那没剩几分钟的小命
The rest of your possibly very short lives
随时都会不保
hinges on this moment.
九头蛇已成功渗透进了神盾局
Hydra has successfully infiltrated S.H.I.E.L.D.
并打进高层
at the highest level.
虽然花了70多年
It only took seven decades,
但今天我们华丽回归了
and today is our coming-out party.
我们得到了拥有九级和10级权限特工的支持
We have the support of the level-9 and level-10 agents.
而那些反抗九头蛇的人也已被除掉
And those who have resisted Hydra have been crossed off...
包括弗瑞局长在内
Director Fury included.
我是来给你个选择  很简单
I'm here to offer you a choice, and a simple one at that.
要不现在就发誓永远坚定不移地
Either swear unwavering loyalty to Hydra
效忠九头蛇
right now for all time...
要不就和弗瑞一个下场
or share Fury's fate.
我不会等很久的
I won't wait long.
除掉我们
Cross us off...
你们其中一人也会一起陪葬
and one of you goes, too.
说得对
Right answer.
我现在相信的只有七个人
The number of people I trust is now seven.
我们的围捕进行得如何
Where are we on the roundup?
我们把所有五级权限以下的特工移至东面关押
We're moving all agents below level five to east holding.
我的手下在监视大部分房间里的麦克风
I have men monitoring microphones placed in most of the rooms.
那我们的突击队呢
And our strike team?
-已强攻飞机  -这只是测试吧
- Has stormed the plane, yes. - That was a-a test?
只有少数人通过
That very few have passed.
我以为我们死定了
I thought we were dead.
你不是九头蛇的人  感谢上帝
You're not Hydra. Thank god.
先别庆祝得太早
Well, don't celebrate just yet.
我们也许不是九头蛇  但你的朋友科尔森
We may not be Hydra, but your friend Coulson --
是九头蛇的人
he is.
我们已抓获科尔森特工和铁骑本人
We captured Agent Coulson and the Cavalry herself.
给楼上打电话  他们会需要援助
Call upstairs. They'll need assistance.
他们正在朝这
They're headed to --
来
here.
我们已经抓住那些狡猾的混蛋了
We caught 'em, the slippery bastards.
梅特工被我打了一枪
Agent May took one of mine in the arm.
科尔森多愁善感  不肯让她失血而死
Softy there wouldn't let her bleed out.
你需要医疗援助吗
Whoa. Do you need medical assistance?
你的佩枪就够了
Just your sidearm.
好了  西蒙斯  你在哪
Okay, come on, Simmons. Where are you?
-向我汇报  -是的  女士
- Report back to me. - Yes, Ma'ma.
怎么样了
What?
我们已经搜查过飞机  女士  没找到
We've searched the plane, ma'am. No sign of it.
飞机着陆时  他们在飞机上
They were on board when it landed.
我们在彻查飞机
We are tearing this plane apart.
他们不知怎么做到的  溜了
They must have... snuck off somehow.
检查一下那些隧道
Check the tunnels.
我要每个走廊驻守两支小队
I want two squads posted in every corridor.
抓住任何人能抓的人
Capture who you can,
但你有权限使用致命武力
but you have permission to use lethal force.
-是的  女士  -你说得对
- Yes, ma'am. - You were right.
我们应该把那架飞机炸掉
We should have blown that plane out of the sky.
你疯了吗  你怎么能说出这种话
Are you mad? How can you be saying this?
九头蛇不会仁慈  我们也不会
Hydra won't show mercy. Neither can we.
科尔森不可能是九头蛇的人
There is no way Coulson is Hydra!
他是个好人  是我们的朋友
He is a good man, a friend!
他是个骗子
He's a liar!
布莱克特工带着他的怀疑来找我
Agent Blake came to me with his suspicions --
说科尔森和其他八级权限的人
that Coulson and the other level eights
涉及某项阴谋
were involved in some sort of conspiracy.
科尔森派他执行一项任务
Then Coulson sent him on an OP
导致他进了重症病房
that put him in the I.C.U.
科尔森不可能做出你说的这些事
Coulson is not capable of what you're insinuating.
雅各布森特工  科尔森的罪行
Agent Jacobson, Coulson's crimes?
招募神盾局的仇敌
Recruiting known enemies of S.H.I.E.L.D.,
违反直接命令  多得不计其数
disobeying a direct order -- multiple counts,
违反国际法
violation of international law.
去营救我们钟爱的霍尔教授
To rescue our beloved Professor Hall,
结果教授却死在他手上
who ended up dead by his hand.
没有上报他门徒阿奇拉·阿玛多尔的罪行
Failure to report the crimes if he's protege Akela Amador.
用在阿奇拉身上的技术被用在
Whose same technology somehow ended up
彼得森先生的脑袋里  你是他干了什么
in the head of Mr. Peterson, and you know his crimes.
你帮我们从千里眼手中救出科尔森
You helped us save Coulson from the Clairvoyant.
但当我们找到这位脑死亡的千里眼时
Yet when we found this brain-dead Clairvoyant,
在我们从他身上盘问出任何秘密之前
Coulson's man Ward shot him
科尔森的手下沃德将他射杀
before we could learn a single thing about him.
这一切都说得通了  西蒙斯特工
The lies add up, Agent Simmons.
你想说他从没瞒过你吗
Are you telling me he's never kept a secret from you?
现在你能做的最糟糕的事就是
The worst thing you can do right now
轻视九头蛇
is to underestimate Hydra.
他们躲在明处
They hide in plain sight.
他们赢得我们的信任  同情
They earn our trust, our sympathy.
他们让我们变得和他们一样
They make us like them.
当你犹豫的时候  他们就除掉你
And when you hesitate, they strike.
如果我们要活下去  就必须学会先发制人
If we're to survive, we must learn to strike first.
见鬼的
Damn.
处理中心就在大厅尽头
That processing center is at the end of that hall.
把你的冰冻枪给我
Give me your icer.
你想怎么做
What are you gonna do?
为你开路
Pave the way for you.
外面有好几百人吧
There's like a hundred guys out there.
12个
12.
五级步兵  基本装甲包
Level-five foot soldiers, basic armor package,
没有其他路可走了
and no other way through.
其他人都指望我们了
The others are depending on us.
但这相当于自杀啊
But it's suicide.
我不死不就行了
Not if I don't die.
如果我死了...
And if I do...
等等
Wh-- slow down.
也许我应该去死
...maybe I deserve to.
我杀了个无辜的人  斯凯
I killed an innocent man, Skye.
你并不知情
You didn't know.
你以为你在做正确的事
You thought you were doing the right thing.
你以为他想要...
You thought he was going to --
伤害你
To hurt you.
如果我们能活着出去  也许我们可以
If we make it out of this, maybe we can...
去喝点东西  就我们俩
grab a drink, you and me.
你是在...
Are you --
还记得在都柏林的酒吧里  你想要...
Remember in that bar in Dublin, you offered to...
谈谈
Talk?
我不想谈
I didn't want to talk.
我必须得公私分明
I needed to keep things compartmentalized.
像和梅那样吗
Like with May?
我不是白痴
I'm not an idiot.
我们生活在同一架飞机上好吧
We live on the same plane together, for god's sake.
和她在一起  我知道我可以
Well, with her, I knew I could.
但是和你...我不想冒这个险
With you... I didn't want to risk it.
我是想和你谈谈  沃德  不是和你上床
I was offering to talk, Ward, not to have sex with you.
我没这么说  我是说
I'm not saying that. I'm saying...
我想要个机会补偿你
I want a chance to take you up on it,
和你谈谈
to have that talk.
我知道我不是那种人
Look, I know I'm not that guy.
我感情不外露  还很无聊
I'm too locked-down, too boring.
如果我们活着出去
When we make it out of this...
好  我们去喝杯东西吧
Yes, let's have a drink.
你说你有可能会死  所以...管他呢
You said you might die, so...what the hell?
把门锁好
Lock the door behind me.
你...
Hey, you...
你真该查查字典里"无聊"是什么意思
You should really look up the word "Boring" in a dictionary.
准备好侵入系统了吗
You ready to hack this system?
谁说我要侵入了
Who said anything about hacking?
在这里  汉德特工
There. Agent Hand.
在东翼的局势分析室
Outside the east wing situation room.
这绝对算得上是严重的局势了
This is definitely a situation.
西蒙斯在吗  找到西蒙斯之前我们哪都不去
Is Simmons there? We don't move until we find Simmons.
我再说一遍  救她最好的机会就是
I'll say it again. Best bet to save her --
利用通风系统到达局势分析室上方
use the ventilation system to get above the sit room.
顺着菲兹的小鼠洞爬下去
Drop down using Fitz's sweet, little mouse hole,
再对着维多利亚·汉德的心脏开两枪
and put two bullets through Victoria Hand's heart.
这也是种选择  长官
Yeah, it's an option, sir.
-都不审问吗  -审问什么
- Without questioning? - Questioning what?
她想快点杀掉我们还是慢慢来吗
Whether she wants to kill us fast or slow?
上次我们这样做时  我们杀了无辜的人
Last time we did that, we shot the wrong man.
因为她想我们这样做
Because she wanted us to!
菲尔  这是为了神盾局的灵魂而战
Phil, this is a battle for S.H.I.E.L.D.'s soul,
我们身处前线
and we're on the front lines.
今天  我们将被历史铭记
History will remember us this day.
没错  为了神盾局的灵魂而战
That's right. It's for S.H.I.E.L.D.'s soul.
不经过考虑的谋杀肯定是...
And murder without consideration is a sure --
考虑  考虑下这个
"Consideration"? Consider this.
她在我手下的油门上安装炸弹
She had one of my men killed
杀死了他
with a bomb rigged to his gas pedal.
还有两个浮在酒店泳池上
The other two were floating in the hotel pool,
他们可不是在游仰泳
and they weren't doing the backstroke.
但我们可以冻住她
But we can just as easily ice her.
你不能冻住像她这样的人
You don't put someone like her on ice.
她让斯凯腹部挨了一枪
She had Skye shot in the stomach --
正中腹腔  就因为她好奇
In the stomach -- because she was curious.
麦克尔·彼得森  劫后余生
Mike Peterson -- burned alive
却被变成了怪物
and turned into some kind of freak.
她用机器折磨你
She tortured you, using the same machine
用的正是给花裙婊子洗脑的那种机器
she used to brainwash that bitch in the flower dress.
而现在  她也许正对西蒙斯特工做同样的事
And right now, she's probably doing the same to Agent Simmons.
我想了很多  朋友
Oh, I've considered it plenty, my friend.
不  西蒙斯不会有事的
No. Simmons will be fine.
现实点吧  孩子
Just being realistic, kid.
我从没提起过
I never mentioned that.
我告诉你  快点杀掉她就是种慈悲
I'm telling you, killing her quick would be a mercy.
我从没说过蕾娜进入过那台机器
I never said Raina had been inside the machine.
我从没跟人说过
I never told that to anybody.
那我肯定是在报告里看到的
I must have read it in a report, then.
你没跟我们在一起
You weren't with us.
重点是  小维达到目的之前还会有多少人受害
The point is, how many more have to suffer before Vic gets hers?
你之后马上出现了
You showed up right after.
你到底想说什么
What are you driving at?
斯凯中枪之后
After Skye was shot.
奎恩说这样会带千里眼找到解药
Quinn said it was so I would lead the Clairvoyant to the cure.
正是这样
That's exactly what I did.
我跟你一起走进去的
I walked you right in there with me.
菲尔
Phil...
今天很难熬  我明白
Look. It's been a rough day. I-I get it.
但你得冷静一下...
But you need to take a second and...
该死
Damn it.
-别动  -不许动
- Freeze! - Don't move!
双手举高
Hands where I can see them.
大伙儿冷静点
Easy, fellas.
快把加勒特特工抓起来
Take Agent Garrett into custody.
他就是被称为千里眼的杀人凶手
He's the murderer they call the Clairvoyant.
他是内鬼
He's a traitor.
先生们
Gentlemen,
我知道西特韦尔特工负责招募你们
I know Agent Sitwell was in charge of filling your ranks,
所以至少你们当中有人知道这种情形该怎么做吧
so at least a few of you know what to do in this situation.
就等你们了
Anytime, boys.
九头蛇万岁
Hail Hydra.
Hail Hydra!
你队里那三个人
Those three men in your unit --
他们问错了问题
I guess they asked the wrong questions.
直到今日  我们做的一切都是为了保密
Until today, it was all about keeping the secret.
你要杀死我们吗
Are you gonna kill us?
我没打算杀死你们
That wasn't my plan, really.
想杀你们  早就可以动手
If it was, I could have done that anytime I wanted.
我和科尔森认识这么久
No, Coulson and I go way back,
早在弗瑞教我们战术时就是知交了
back to the days when Fury was teaching us tactics --
探查转角  注意上下
clearing corners, slicing the pie.
还记得吗  菲尔
Remember, Phil?
弗瑞会弄死你的
Fury would bury you for this.
也许吧
Probably.
相反  他只要在自己的坟里给我腾点地方就行了
Instead, he'll just have to roll over in his grave.
他一定发现了我们的秘密
He must have uncovered our secret.
大领导采取了必要措施
Top brass did what they had to do.
怪不得我们突然"走出了阴影"
Explains why we've suddenly come "out of the shadows."
我得加一句  完全没觉得不便
Not a minor inconvenience, I might add.
大领导
"Top brass"?
是啊  最顶头的领导
Oh, my, yes. Tip-top.
我们有个好幌子
We had a good thing going, too --
使劲挥舞神盾局的大旗
waving the S.H.I.E.L.D. flag as hard as we could.
看来现在我们是要变色了
I guess we'll be changing colors now.
为了九头蛇
For Hydra?
你真相信那套鬼话
You really believe all that crap --
传播死亡与毁灭
spreading death and destruction?
我倒称不上是忠实信徒
I wouldn't say I'm a true believer.
这么说吧
Let's just say I felt
我感到风向有变  于是顺势转舵了
the wind changing direction and swung my sail.
你也该这么做
You really should, too.
就算是死  我都不会为九头蛇服务
I would die before serving Hydra,
狗娘养的
you sick son of a bitch.
真不想这么说
I hate to tell you, but...
但你一直在为九头蛇服务
you've been serving Hydra all along.
看来你只有死路一条了
I guess death is the only alternative.
真悲伤啊  我还当你是朋友呢
It's a sad thing. I consider you a friend.
听说你没死我可是高兴得很
I was happy when I heard you'd made it through.
高兴到折磨了我三天
So happy you had me tortured for three days
就为查明他们是怎么做到的
to find out how they did it.
折磨你我也不好受
I didn't enjoy that.
菲尔  我说真的
Phil, t-this is me being honest.
不  约翰  你就是个疯子
No, John. This is you being a psychopath.
我知道你誓死追随他  所以...
I know you'd follow him to the grave, so...
至于你  菲兹特工  你要愿意的话
As for you, Agent Fitz, you'll hold a very high rank,
将拥有更高级别  掌管技术部门
run our tech division if you volunteer.
如若不然  你将一无所有  痛苦不堪
If not, you'll have no rank and a lot of pain.
当然了  不管怎样  你都要为我们服务
Of course, either way, your services will be required.
你会为你的所作所为付出代价的
You're gonna suffer for what you've done.
而我
And I --
我绝饶不了你
I plan on being a very big part of that.
我喜欢你  孩子
I like you, kid.
好了  开枪吧
All right. Let them have it.
那一个打在膝盖上
But shoot that one in the kneecaps.
就这样了
Was that all of them?
我以为会更猛一点...
It wasn't as big as I thought --
科尔森
Coulson.
举起手来
Heads up!
放下武器
Drop your weapon!
不许动
Don't move!
我不是九头蛇
I'm not Hydra.
我们听到了一切
We heard...everything.
谁是
Who is?
它渗入得有多深
How deep does it go?
美国队长在三叉戟总部战胜了
Captain America has defeated the helicarriers
直升航母
at the Triskelion.
但他状态未知
But his status is unknown.
神盾局沦陷了
And S.H.I.E.L.D. has fallen.
九头蛇团体控制了
Hyrda factions have taken control
东非总部和树屋
of our East African headquarters and the treehouse.
那些只是我们已知的
And those are just the ones we know of.
场面会一片混乱  争权夺势
It's gonna be a scramble, a power grab.
我会去冷藏库  至少那里是安全的
I'll head to the fridge. At least that facility is secure.
我没必要提醒你
I don't need to remind you
保持那样有多么重要
how imperative it is that it stay that way.
我会给加勒特特工
And I'll find Agent Garrett
找个冷藏库里最小最黑暗的隔间
the smallest, darkest cell in the icebox.
我想亲自打开那个隔间
I'd like to turn the key on that cell myself...
如果你不介意  长官
if you don't mind, sir.
他曾是我的监管人员
He was my S.O.
我觉得我...
I feel I...
我该知道的
I should have known.
这是我的职责...
It was my duty to --
没人知道  我也不知道
No one knew. I didn't know.
他就是这样打败我们的  做我们的朋友
That's how he beat us -- by being a friend.
我和那个混蛋共处了多年
I spent years with that bastard.
尊敬他
Looked up to him.
我想看他遭受痛苦
I want to see him suffer.
不介意有人陪我去
Don't mind the company,
而且我需要你这样的人才
and I can always use a man of your skills.
如果你可以  在中心收拾残局
Pick up the pieces here at the hub if you can,
然后...
and, uh...
只用这个进行联络
only communicate using one of these.
我俩可能是神盾局里既不是九头蛇
You and I may be the highest-ranking S.H.I.E.L.D. agents
又尚未死去的最高级特工了
who aren't Hyrda or dead...
反正那也不重要了
Not that that means anything now.
我们只有彼此
All we have is each other.
保持联系  科尔森特工
So stay in touch, Agent Coulson.
我想你可以叫我菲尔
I guess you can... call me Phil.
都没了
It's all gone.
至少成了碎片
In pieces, at least.
斯凯  尽量
Skye, try to restore
从飞机系统的固件里恢复信息
some of the firmware in the plane's systems.
菲兹·西蒙斯  召集一支队伍
Fitz-Simmons, get a crew together.
帮梅修补漏洞
Help May patch the holes.
你还想让我一起吗
You still want me on board?
你不再是朋友
You're not a friend.
但我相信你是个盟友
But I do believe you're an ally.
我们需要所有盟友
We need all the allies we can get.
我们接下来打算怎么办
What are we planning to do next?
活下去
Survive.
-航线锁定了  女士  -很好
- Course is locked, ma'am. - Good.
他现在不说故事了啊
He's not telling stories now, is he?
你知道我在想什么吗  加勒特特工
You know what I'm thinking, Agent Garrett?
我想着冷藏库里的冰柜
I'm thinking the icebox of the fridge
对你而言太过舒适了
is a little too comfortable for you.
也许我们该把你放到更深的地下
Maybe we should put you a little deeper underground.
你觉得呢  沃德特工
What do you think, Agent Ward?
你以前对错误的千里眼开过枪
You shot the wrong clairvoyant before.
想对真正的千里眼开枪吗
Care to shoot the right one?
我跟你说过  有次我是秘密卧底的事儿吗
Did I tell you about this one time I was deep undercover?
西西里当地的支援当然没出现
The Sicilian backup team a no-show, of course.
所以我从天而降
So I dropped in through the skylight,
用尽了最后一颗子弹
used up my whole mag,
然后用信号弹射中了剩下的那个家伙
and I hit the final guy in the chest with a flare gun.
你真该瞧瞧那玩意爆炸时
Boy, you should have seen the look
他脸上的表情
on his face when that thing went off.
天啊  他都不知道自己是被什么打中的
Oh, man, he didn't know what hit him.